const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following drugs is not used for leprosy treatment anymore?","answers":[{"option":"Ethionamide","bool":false},{"option":"Thalidomide","bool":true},{"option":"Dapsone","bool":false},{"option":"Clofazimine","bool":false},{"option":"Rifampin","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Ingestion of which of the following cause(s) human cysticercosis?","answers":[{"option":"Taenia solium eggs","bool":true},{"option":"Taenia saginata eggs and larvae","bool":false},{"option":"Taenia saginata larvae","bool":false},{"option":"Taenia saginata eggs","bool":false},{"option":"Pork containing cysticerci","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following laboratory tests is useful for the management of patients infected with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatitis C virus (HCV) DNA","bool":false},{"option":"White blood cell count","bool":false},{"option":"CD4-positive T cell count","bool":true},{"option":"HIV antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"p24 antigen","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Curschmann spirals are spiral-shaped mucus plugs that arise from subepithelial mucus glands in bronchi. These spirals are associated with many lung diseases. Which of the following diseases presents with these spirals?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchial asthma","bool":true},{"option":"Lobar pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchiectasis","bool":false},{"option":"Aspergillosis","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 3-year-old boy is brought to the outpatient department by his parents with a complaint of loose stools for the past 2 days. On examination, the child is found to be active with no visible signs of dehydration. What is the management for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"ORS 100-200ml after each loose motion","bool":true},{"option":"No fluids","bool":false},{"option":"Mineral water","bool":false},{"option":"I/V ringer lactate","bool":false},{"option":"I/V normal saline","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Mumps virus is an RNA virus that is transmitted through respiratory droplets and has an incubation period of 18-21 days. It presents with fever, malaise, and anorexia followed by unilateral or bilateral parotid swelling. How is mumps diagnosed?","answers":[{"option":"Complement fixation test","bool":false},{"option":"Hemagglutination inhibition test","bool":false},{"option":"Mumps skin test","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal fluid culture","bool":false},{"option":"Clinical examination","bool":true}]},{"id":6,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Atopic asthma is a type-1 hypersensitivity reaction that involves the lower respiratory tract. It occurs as a result of inhalation of antigen that causes the degranulation of sensitized mast cells present in the nasal or bronchiolar mucosa. This disease is mostly present in which age group?","answers":[{"option":"Any age","bool":false},{"option":"Childhood","bool":true},{"option":"Adulthood","bool":false},{"option":"Old age","bool":false},{"option":"Infancy","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 17-year-old boy comes to the outpatient department with the complaint of high-grade, intermittent fever for the past 3 days. He also complains of associated rigor and chills and intense backache. Examination reveals a petechial rash over his shins. His complete blood count (CBC) reveals; hemoglobin 12.1 g/dL, total leukocyte count (TLC) 2.9 x 10^3/L, and platelets 39 x 10^3/L. What is the patient suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Enteric fever","bool":false},{"option":"Acute malaria","bool":false},{"option":"Meningococcal meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue fever","bool":true},{"option":"Infective endocarditis","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Neisseria gonorrhoeae, when Gram-stained and viewed microscopically, appears as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Gram negative cocci in grape like cluster","bool":false},{"option":"Gram positive cocci in grape like cluster","bool":false},{"option":"Gram negative rods","bool":false},{"option":"Gram positive diplococci","bool":false},{"option":"Gram negative diplococci","bool":true}]},{"id":9,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following drugs is used for the treatment of inoperable hydatid cysts?","answers":[{"option":"Albendazole","bool":true},{"option":"Fluconazole","bool":false},{"option":"Metronidazole","bool":false},{"option":"Corticosteroid","bool":false},{"option":"Ciprofloxacin","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following negligences refers to defective hospital care and equipment, incompetent employees, and failure to maintain the standards of care?","answers":[{"option":"Third party negligence","bool":false},{"option":"Civil negligence","bool":false},{"option":"Contributory negligence","bool":false},{"option":"Criminal negligence","bool":false},{"option":"Corporate negligence","bool":true}]},{"id":11,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"SIRS is a life-threatening disease that can lead to multiple organ failure, if not treated immediately. What does it stand for?","answers":[{"option":"It stands for systems involved in infection syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"It stands for system inflammation related syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"It stands for septicemic inflammation related syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"It stands for systemic inflammatory response syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"It stands for systematic infection related syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 1-year-old girl is brought by her parents to the outpatient department (OPD) with complaints of fever and rashes. The doctor on-duty suspects measles. At what stage can measles spread to others?","answers":[{"option":"Patient remains infectious up to 2 weeks after the appearance of rashes","bool":false},{"option":"Three days before the appearance of rash upto 4 to 6 days after its onset","bool":true},{"option":"Seven days before the appearance of rash upto 5 days after its onset","bool":false},{"option":"The day of appearance of rash till 7 days after the onset","bool":false},{"option":"Ten days before the appearance of rash upto 7 days after its onset","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following is the definitive host of the tiny tapeworm, Echinococcus granulosus?","answers":[{"option":"Cattle","bool":false},{"option":"Camel","bool":false},{"option":"Sheep","bool":false},{"option":"Human","bool":false},{"option":"Dogs","bool":true}]},{"id":14,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which drug inhibits the protein synthesis by reversibly binding to the 50S subunit of the bacterial ribosome and thereby restricting the formation of peptide bonds?","answers":[{"option":"Actinomycin-D","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin","bool":false},{"option":"Chloramphenicol","bool":true},{"option":"Ciprofloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Cephalosporins","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 28-year-old male comes to the emergency room with complaints of rising fever for the past 4 days, which was initially low grade and has become high grade. He also complains of generalized weakness and abdominal pain. On general examinations, the vitals are; blood pressure: 100/60 mm Hg, pulse: 64 beats per minute, temperature:  103 Â°F, respiratory rate: 22 breaths per minute. The systemic examination is unremarkable. What is the patient most likely suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Malaria","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue","bool":false},{"option":"Typhoid","bool":true},{"option":"Brucellosis","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"What is the most commonly proposed mechanism for the cause of sarcoidosis?","answers":[{"option":"Drug-induced","bool":false},{"option":"Fungal infection","bool":false},{"option":"Viral infection","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial infection","bool":false},{"option":"Disordered immune regulation","bool":true}]},{"id":17,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 20-year-old male presents to the emergency department with complaints of fever, fatigue, and headache for the past 10 days. He is now experiencing agitation and hallucination, with aggressive behavior. History suggests that he suffered a dog bite 4 weeks ago. On examination, he is found to have excessive salivation, hyperreflexia, and spasticity. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Tetanus","bool":false},{"option":"Rabies","bool":true},{"option":"Psychosis","bool":false},{"option":"Creutzfeldt-Jacob disease","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes simplex encephalitis","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following is the mediator responsible for causing fever in systemic inflammatory response syndrome (SIRS)?","answers":[{"option":"Hageman factor","bool":false},{"option":"Interleukin-1","bool":true},{"option":"Bradykinin","bool":false},{"option":"Nitric oxide","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following side effects is not associated with fluoroquinolones?","answers":[{"option":"Hallucinations","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatotoxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Deafness","bool":true},{"option":"Damage to growing cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Phototoxicity","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"An afebrile patient comes to the outpatient department with a complaint of passing large number of stools frequently. On microscopic examination of the stool, no red blood cells and white blood cells are found. Which of the following conditions best relate to the patient's complaint?","answers":[{"option":"Watery diarrhea","bool":true},{"option":"Bloody diarrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Indigestion","bool":false},{"option":"Dysentery","bool":false},{"option":"Infectious","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A young girl is admitted to the hospital with frequent bouts of fever that are associated with rigor and chills. On examination of blood film, crescent banana-shaped structures are seen. Her urine turns black on exposure to air. Which of the following organisms is the cause of the patient's symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Dengue virus","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium falciparum","bool":true},{"option":"Plasmodium malariae","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium vivax","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A urea breath test is performed on a patient of which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Enterocolitis","bool":false},{"option":"Enteric fever","bool":false},{"option":"Acid peptic disease","bool":true},{"option":"Cholera","bool":false},{"option":"Liver abscess","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following is a typical clinical finding in the case of cryptosporidiosis?","answers":[{"option":"Watery diarrhea in immunocompetent patients for long duration","bool":false},{"option":"Non bloody diarrhea in immunocompetent patients for long duration","bool":false},{"option":"Watery diarrhea in immunocompetent patients for short duration","bool":true},{"option":"Self limiting diarrhea in immunocompromised patients","bool":false},{"option":"Bloody diarrhea in immunocompetent patients for short duration","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"When taking the history of diarrhea in children, what is the most important combination of signs or symptoms that is needed to be asked?","answers":[{"option":"Frequency and smell","bool":false},{"option":"Color and consistency","bool":false},{"option":"Frequency and consistency","bool":false},{"option":"Duration and smell","bool":false},{"option":"Color and duration","bool":true}]},{"id":25,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"What is the treatment of choice for hydatid disease?","answers":[{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false},{"option":"Mebendazole","bool":false},{"option":"Ivermectin","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrantel pamoate","bool":false},{"option":"Albendazole","bool":true}]},{"id":26,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 20-year-old college student, who has returned from his trip to India, now presents with fever and malaise. His peripheral blood smear confirms the presence of malaria species. His physician prescribes him chloroquine and asks him to take rest at home. What is the problem with this physician's choice of treatment of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"He should also have prescribed a drug to treat yellow fever because these diseases are often transmitted together","bool":false},{"option":"Primaquine is not the drug of choice, he should have prescribed albendazole","bool":false},{"option":"Chloroquine is unnecessary because malaria infection is short lived and benign","bool":false},{"option":"He should have prescribed primaquine in addition to chloroquine","bool":true},{"option":"There is nothing wrong with this prescription","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"All the travelers who are exposed to the risk of yellow fever or pass through the endemic zones of yellow fever should have a valid vaccination card for yellow fever before they enter a country.  If any of them fails to possess the card, which of the following should be done?","answers":[{"option":"Sent back","bool":false},{"option":"Kept in isolation","bool":false},{"option":"Treated","bool":false},{"option":"Immunized","bool":false},{"option":"Kept in quarantine","bool":true}]},{"id":28,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 40-year-old male is bitten by a sandfly and has presented to the outpatient department with an ulcerated red papule. The doctor suspects infection with Leishmania tropica. Which of the following is found in the skin lesion smear for the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Hypnozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Amastigotes","bool":true},{"option":"Trophozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Merozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Promastigotes","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following is the most important toxicity of amphotericin B?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatotoxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Nephrotoxicity","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Bone marrow depression","bool":false},{"option":"Neurotoxicity","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Pap smear of a 30-year-old female, who is admitted to the hospital, shows intraepithelial neoplasia. To confirm the type of human papillomavirus (HPV), a polymerase chain reaction (PCR) is carried out, which shows the presence of HPV-16 and HPV-18 genotypes of human papillomavirus. Which one of the following is correct about human papillomavirus?","answers":[{"option":"HPV-16 and HPV-18 cause genital warts","bool":false},{"option":"Skin warts are most common","bool":false},{"option":"Clinical diagnosis is not helpful","bool":false},{"option":"Vertical transmission is not found","bool":false},{"option":"Koilocytes are the hallmark of infection","bool":true}]},{"id":31,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"In a nearby daycare center, a group of children develops severe perianal itching and pruritis. Their mothers also identify pumpkin seed-like structures in children's stools. Which of the following organisms is the most likely cause of these symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Ascaris","bool":false},{"option":"Hymenolepis nana","bool":false},{"option":"Trichuris trichiura","bool":false},{"option":"Hook worm","bool":false},{"option":"Enterobius vermicularis","bool":true}]},{"id":32,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 35-year-old male comes to the outpatient department (OPD) with complaints of high-grade fever associated with chills, nausea, vomiting. The doctor diagnoses him with the case of malaria caused by Plasmodium falciparum. Which of the following is the life-threatening complication of this type of malaria?","answers":[{"option":"Bone marrow failure","bool":false},{"option":"Acute hepatic failure","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral malaria","bool":true},{"option":"Anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Splenomegaly","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"What is the first-line medication for the treatment of enteric fever?","answers":[{"option":"Azithromycin","bool":false},{"option":"Meropenem","bool":false},{"option":"Co-amoxiclav","bool":false},{"option":"Ceftriaxone","bool":false},{"option":"Ciprofloxacin","bool":true}]},{"id":34,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"An 18-year-old boy, who has migrated from Quetta to Karachi, presents to the outpatient department with complaints of fever, abdominal pain, lethargy, and reduced appetite since the past week. History suggests that he is working at a tandoor (roti) shop for the last 3 months and lives in an unhygienic environment. He drinks tap water. On examination, a faint, salmon-colored, maculopapular rash is noticed on his trunk. Apart from a complete blood count (CBC), what is the next most appropriate test to diagnose his illness?","answers":[{"option":"Blood for culture and sensitivity","bool":true},{"option":"Hepatitis A and E antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Stool for ova and parasite","bool":false},{"option":"Urine for culture and sensitivity","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound abdomen","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following refers to the restriction of the movement of a sick person in order to stop the spread of certain diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Isolation","bool":true},{"option":"Secondary prevention","bool":false},{"option":"Rehabilitation","bool":false},{"option":"Quarantine","bool":false},{"option":"Primordial prevention","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 27-year-old boy is started with a human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) drug regimen after the diagnosis of HIV infection. Which of the following drugs blocks the cleavage of HIV polyproteins?","answers":[{"option":"Maraviroc","bool":false},{"option":"Enfuvirtide","bool":false},{"option":"Delavirdine","bool":false},{"option":"Stavudine","bool":false},{"option":"Darunavir","bool":true}]},{"id":37,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 68-year-old male presents to the emergency room with complaints of diarrhea, vomiting, and abdominal pain. History suggests that he is immunocompromised and suffering from prostate carcinoma for the past 6 years. His laboratory investigations reveal low hemoglobin, raised erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR), and decreased total leukocyte count (TLC). His diagnosis is made by detecting oocysts in fecal smear with the help of a modified Kinyoun acid-fast stain. Which of the following organisms is responsible for his symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Cryptosporidium hominis","bool":true},{"option":"Entamoeba histolytica","bool":false},{"option":"Entamoeba dispar","bool":false},{"option":"Trichomonas vaginalis","bool":false},{"option":"Giardia lamblia","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A young male experiences skin discoloration after the start of drug therapy for leprosy. His skin color ranges from red-brown to black. Which of the following drugs causes this side effect?","answers":[{"option":"Rifabutin","bool":false},{"option":"Acedapsone","bool":false},{"option":"Sulfadoxine","bool":false},{"option":"Clofazimine","bool":true},{"option":"Dapsone","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Leprosy (also known as Hansen's disease) can be treated efficiently with dapsone and rifampin along with clofazimine in multibacillary cases. Which of the following enzymes is inhibited by one of the leprosy drugs mentioned?","answers":[{"option":"Dihydropteroate synthetase enzyme","bool":true},{"option":"Acetyltransferase enzyme","bool":false},{"option":"Dihydrofolate reductase enzyme","bool":false},{"option":"DNA-gyrase enzyme","bool":false},{"option":"Topoisomerase IV enzyme","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 12-year-old boy presents to the emergency room with complaints of fever and abdominal cramps, followed by diarrhea.  The diarrhea was initially watery but now contains blood and mucus. Which organism is the cause of diarrhea and dysentery?","answers":[{"option":"Proteus mirabilis","bool":false},{"option":"Shigella spp","bool":true},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":false},{"option":"Vibrio cholerae","bool":false},{"option":"Helicobacter pylori","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"In the case of the transfer of malaria protozoa by the mosquito, which of the following forms is transferred?","answers":[{"option":"Gametocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Schizonts","bool":false},{"option":"Merozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Sporozoites","bool":true},{"option":"Hypnozoites","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"What is an unusual, more than expected occurrence of a disease or any event related to health, in a community, called?","answers":[{"option":"Endemic","bool":false},{"option":"Pandemic","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperendemic","bool":false},{"option":"Sporadic","bool":false},{"option":"Epidemic","bool":true}]},{"id":43,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 46-year-old female suffers an injury on her foot with a rusty nail while walking barefoot on her lawn. She rushes to the emergency department and seeks medical help. The doctor cleans her wound with normal saline and dresses her wound. Which of the following is most likely to cause an infection in her case?","answers":[{"option":"Clostridium difficile","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium sordellii","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium perfringens","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium tetani","bool":true},{"option":"Clostridium botulinum","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following is/are mediators of hypotension?","answers":[{"option":"C5a","bool":false},{"option":"Hageman factor","bool":false},{"option":"Bradykinin and nitric oxide","bool":true},{"option":"C3a","bool":false},{"option":"Interleukin-1","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A young man presents to the emergency department with a complaint of non-bloody diarrhea for the past 3 days. Stool culture is ordered. The culture reveals gram-negative rods with lactose fermenting colonies. Which of the following organisms is responsible for his symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Shigella","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":true},{"option":"Vibrio cholerae","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococci","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 45-year-old male presents to the clinic with a palpable mass in the right hypochondrium. A complete blood count shows eosinophilia and a chest X-ray shows calcification below the right diaphragm. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Amoebic liver abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatocellular carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Pyogenic liver abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Metastases due to malignancy","bool":false},{"option":"Hydatid liver disease with calcification","bool":true}]},{"id":47,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 20-year-old unconscious male is brought to the emergency room with profuse bleeding from the incised wound on his left wrist. Which of the following types of consent will be used to treat this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Written consent","bool":false},{"option":"Implied consent","bool":true},{"option":"No need of consent","bool":false},{"option":"Expressed consent","bool":false},{"option":"Oral consent","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following clinical features is typically the first sign of tetanus?","answers":[{"option":"Opisthotonus","bool":false},{"option":"Uncontrolled urination","bool":false},{"option":"Trismus","bool":true},{"option":"Reflex spasms","bool":false},{"option":"Risus sardonicus","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A young male, living in a non-malarious area, plans to visit an area where chloroquine-resistant Plasmodium falciparum is common. He is known to be intolerant to mefloquine and his glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase (G6PD) status is not known. Which of the following drugs will be prescribed to him for prophylaxis?","answers":[{"option":"Amoquine","bool":false},{"option":"Primaquine","bool":false},{"option":"Doxycycline","bool":true},{"option":"Amodiaquine","bool":false},{"option":"Quinine","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following is a drug of choice for cerebral cysticercosis?","answers":[{"option":"Prednisolone","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocortisone","bool":false},{"option":"Ceftriaxone","bool":false},{"option":"Albendazole","bool":true},{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Breakbone fever is another name for which of the following diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Yellow fever","bool":false},{"option":"Congo fever","bool":false},{"option":"Ebola fever","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue fever","bool":true},{"option":"Lassa fever","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following bacteria is known to be a usual cause of bloody diarrhea?","answers":[{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Entamoeba histolytica","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella typhi","bool":false},{"option":"Helicobacter pylori","bool":false},{"option":"Shigella","bool":true}]},{"id":53,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of peripheral nerve thickening?","answers":[{"option":"Alcoholism","bool":false},{"option":"Amyloidosis","bool":false},{"option":"HIV infection","bool":false},{"option":"Charcot-Marie-Tooth Disease","bool":false},{"option":"Leprosy","bool":true}]},{"id":54,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 4-year-old child is brought to the clinic with a history of fever and right knee swelling for the past one week. For the last month, he has been having dysuria on and off and urethral discharge. On examination, in addition to signs of the acute arthritis of the right knee, there is a pustular rash on his leg. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Disseminated Neisseria gonorrhoeae infection","bool":true},{"option":"Candidiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Chlamydia trachomatis infection","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes simplex infection","bool":false},{"option":"Syphilis","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 45-year-old male comes to his doctor with the chief complaints of fever, night sweats, and increased episodes of diarrhea during the past month. He has lost 30 pounds over the past 4 months. On physical exam, he has oral thrush and cervical lymphadenopathy. The patient has a contact history as well. The clinician has a strong suspicion of human immune deficiency virus (HIV) infection. Which of the following is the confirmatory test for HIV infection?","answers":[{"option":"Western blot test","bool":true},{"option":"Viral genome amplification (PCP)","bool":false},{"option":"Virus culture","bool":false},{"option":"Antigen/antibody detection (ELISA)","bool":false},{"option":"Point of care test (POT)","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 38-year-old male presents to the outpatient department with complaints of generalized weakness and chronic diarrhea. He has had excessive weight loss over the past few months. He gives a history of drug abuse. Suspecting HIV, which screening test should be advised?","answers":[{"option":"Western blot","bool":false},{"option":"ELISA","bool":true},{"option":"HIV viral load test","bool":false},{"option":"Absolute CD4âº lymphocyte count","bool":false},{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following is not used for the management of Clostridium difficile-associated diarrhea?","answers":[{"option":"Intravenous immunoglobulin","bool":false},{"option":"Stop the offending antibiotic","bool":false},{"option":"Patient should be isolated","bool":false},{"option":"Metronidazole","bool":false},{"option":"Intravenous vancomycin","bool":true}]},{"id":58,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"The presumptive diagnosis of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection is sometimes made with the help of antibodies found in the patient's serum using enzyme-linked immunoassay (ELISA). Which test is confirmatory for HIV infection?","answers":[{"option":"Antigen/antibody detection (ELISA)","bool":false},{"option":"Point of care testing (POCT)","bool":false},{"option":"Western blot test","bool":true},{"option":"Viral genome amplification (PCR)","bool":false},{"option":"Virus culture","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following can not be prevented by the protective measures taken against the mosquitoes?","answers":[{"option":"Congo Crimean hemorrhagic fever","bool":true},{"option":"Chikungunya fever","bool":false},{"option":"Yellow fever","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue fever","bool":false},{"option":"Malaria fever","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following is correct for Enterobius vermicularis?","answers":[{"option":"It is transmitted by mosquito","bool":false},{"option":"It can cause elephantiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Its trophozoites can be recovered from diarrheal stools","bool":false},{"option":"Perianal pruritus is its most prominent symptom","bool":true},{"option":"Its infection occurs in animals","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following drugs is/are contraindicated in dengue?","answers":[{"option":"Antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"NSAID and aspirin","bool":true},{"option":"Antimalarial","bool":false},{"option":"Antiemetics","bool":false},{"option":"Acetaminophen","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which can help in the diagnosis of factitious fever?","answers":[{"option":"Increased ESR and CRP","bool":false},{"option":"Normal temperature during supervised measurement","bool":true},{"option":"A patient who looks unwell","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of diurnal variation","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of swelling during defervescence","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"During the fight, Faisal amputates Shahid's finger with a sharp knife. Which of the following criminal act has Faisal caused?","answers":[{"option":"Jaifah","bool":false},{"option":"Itlaf-i-salahiyyat-i-udw","bool":false},{"option":"Itlaf-i-udw","bool":true},{"option":"Jurh","bool":false},{"option":"Shajjah","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"During a police encounter, a dacoit is shot dead. Who will carry out the investigation in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Medico-legal officer of the area","bool":false},{"option":"The magistrate","bool":true},{"option":"The coroner","bool":false},{"option":"The police","bool":false},{"option":"The panchas","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A doctor receives 5 cases of cholera together at his private clinic in Lahore. He should report these cases to which of the following authorities?","answers":[{"option":"District nazim","bool":false},{"option":"Area magistrate","bool":false},{"option":"District health authorities","bool":true},{"option":"District police station","bool":false},{"option":"Local police station","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 27-year-old pregnant lady arrives at the emergency with extreme labor pain and is rushed to the labor room for the delivery. Her history suggests that she previously had a herpes simplex virus 2 infection.  Which of the following is correct for neonatal herpes?","answers":[{"option":"Neonatal infection is more likely to occur when mother is suffering from recurrent infection","bool":false},{"option":"Amount of virus produced during primary infection is less than produced in a secondary infection","bool":false},{"option":"Neonatal herpes chiefly originates from contact with vesicular lesions within the birth canal","bool":true},{"option":"Vaginal delivery has lesser chances of delivering infection to neonate as compared with caesarean section","bool":false},{"option":"Mother would pass IgM antibodies which can protect neonate from disseminated infection","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following drugs inhibits the microtubule formation in roundworm, pinworm, and hookworm infections and can eradicate worm infestation?","answers":[{"option":"Mebendazole","bool":true},{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false},{"option":"Thiabendazole","bool":false},{"option":"Niclosamide","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrantel pamoate","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"What is the mechanism of action of niclosamide?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibition of phosphorylation of ADP in some species of helminths","bool":true},{"option":"Lysis of helminthic proteins through decrease in intracellular pH","bool":false},{"option":"Blocking acetylcholine transmission at the myoneural junction and paralysis of helminths","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of microtubule synthesis in helminths and irreversible impairment of glucose uptake","bool":false},{"option":"Increasing cell membrane permeability for calcium, resulting in paralysis, dislodgement and death of helminths","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 24-year-old farmer comes to the outpatient department with a complaint of difficulty in opening his mouth. He also has a small wound in the heel of his right foot. On examination, generalized body stiffness is found. He is rushed to the emergency room for further evaluation of suspected tetanus. Which of the following is an important step in the management of tetanus?","answers":[{"option":"Administer adsorbed tetanus toxoid (TT)","bool":false},{"option":"Administer human tetanus immunoglobulin (HTIG)","bool":true},{"option":"Perform endotracheal intubation","bool":false},{"option":"Give prophylactic heparin","bool":false},{"option":"Give intravenous metronidazole","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 30-year-old man presents to the medical outpatient department with a complaint of pain during urination. He also complains of purulent urethral discharge and gives a history of sexual contact 7 days ago. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Urinary tract infection","bool":false},{"option":"Chlamydial urethritis","bool":false},{"option":"Primary syphilis","bool":false},{"option":"Trichomonas infection","bool":false},{"option":"Gonorrhea","bool":true}]},{"id":71,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A young patient comes to the clinic with a complaint of abdominal pain for 2 days, accompanied by a fever for the past one day. Laboratory results show increased total leukocyte count (TLC) and raised erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR). The doctor suspects the acute inflammation of the intestine. Which of the following is responsible for his symptoms and acute inflammation?","answers":[{"option":"Interlukin-24","bool":false},{"option":"Interlukin-23","bool":false},{"option":"Interlukin-1","bool":true},{"option":"Histamine","bool":false},{"option":"Lipoxin","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 2-year-old boy is brought by his parents to the emergency room with papulovesicular rash present on the trunk, head, and extremities. His parents also mention the history of fever and malaise for the past 4 days. His mother further adds that the same rash has also presented on their neighbor's child.  What is the most likely causative agent?","answers":[{"option":"Measles virus","bool":false},{"option":"Varicella - zoster virus","bool":true},{"option":"Mumps virus","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes simplex II","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes simplex I","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A middle-aged man presents to the outpatient department with complaints of headache, vomiting, and seizures after he ate undercooked pork. Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) of the brain is carried out, which reveals multiple lesions bilaterally. The doctor diagnosed him with cysticercosis of the brain. Which of the following parasites is responsible for cysticercosis?","answers":[{"option":"Taenia saginata","bool":false},{"option":"Diphyllobothrium latum","bool":false},{"option":"Echinococcus granulosus","bool":false},{"option":"Taenia solium","bool":true},{"option":"Hymenolepis nana","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Ali and Ahmed get into a fight outside the school. Ali punches Ahmed hard enough to cause a fracture of the mandible along with the anterior dislocation. Which type of injury has Ali caused?","answers":[{"option":"Shajjah-i-mudihah","bool":false},{"option":"Shajjah-i-munaqqilah","bool":true},{"option":"Shajjah-i-ammah","bool":false},{"option":"Shajjah-i-khafifah","bool":false},{"option":"Shajjah-i-damighah","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 14-year-old girl presents to the clinic with complaints of fever, headache, and neck rigidity. Cerebrospinal fluid examination reveals increased polymorphonuclear cells and Gram staining reveals the presence of gram-negative diplococci. Which of the following is the most likely causative micro-organism?","answers":[{"option":"Branhamella species","bool":false},{"option":"Moraxella catarrhalis","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria meningitidis","bool":true},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria gonorrhoeae","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 36-year-old male presents to the outpatient department with complaints of fever, weakness , weight loss and massive splenomegaly. He is suspected to be infected by Leishmania donovani, which is the cause of kala azar (visceral leishmaniasis). Which system of the body is affected by this infection?","answers":[{"option":"Reticuloendothelial system","bool":true},{"option":"Immune system","bool":false},{"option":"Gastrointestinal system","bool":false},{"option":"Endocrine system","bool":false},{"option":"Nervous system","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"In dengue infection, the hemorrhagic shock syndrome occurs due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Interleukin-1 acting on hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Increased vascular permeability and thrombocytopenia due to complement activity","bool":true},{"option":"High grade fever","bool":false},{"option":"Depletion of water and electrolytes","bool":false},{"option":"Ulceration of gastrointestinal tract","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"In which of the following helminthic infestation albendazole is the drug of choice?","answers":[{"option":"Hydatid disease","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Ascariasis","bool":false},{"option":"Strongyloidiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Ankylostomiasis","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 10-year-old boy is brought to the outpatient department with a complaint of diarrhea. On examination, he is seen to have rectal prolapse. His stool analysis shows barrel-shaped eggs with plugs at each end. Which one of the following nematodes is most likely to be involved?","answers":[{"option":"Trichinella","bool":false},{"option":"Strongyloides","bool":false},{"option":"Wuchereria bancrofti","bool":false},{"option":"Trichuris","bool":true},{"option":"Loa loa","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 10-year-old boy is brought to the emergency room with profuse diarrhea. He has now developed kidney failure, thrombocytopenia, and hemolytic anemia. His blood smear reveals fragmented red blood cells called\r\nschistocytes. What is the most likely causative agent?","answers":[{"option":"Enterotoxigenic E. coli","bool":false},{"option":"Enteroaggregative E. coli","bool":false},{"option":"Enteropathogenic E. coli","bool":false},{"option":"Enterohemorrhagic E. coli","bool":true},{"option":"Enteroinvasive E. coli","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 10-year-old boy is brought to the emergency room with complaints of fever and abdominal cramps, followed by diarrhea which was initially watery but later contained blood and mucus. Colorless colonies are seen on MacConkey's agar. Which of the following characteristics is correct regarding the organism involved?","answers":[{"option":"O antigen","bool":true},{"option":"Lactose-fermenters","bool":false},{"option":"Produce H2S","bool":false},{"option":"Motile","bool":false},{"option":"High ID50","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 12-year-old boy comes to the outpatient department with abdominal pain. He is barefooted, pale, and malnourished, with a protruded abdomen. Physical examination reveals anemia. Which of the following parasites will be identified from stool examination?","answers":[{"option":"Ascaris lumbricoides","bool":false},{"option":"Enterobius vermicularis","bool":false},{"option":"Ancylostoma duodenale","bool":true},{"option":"Balantidium coli","bool":false},{"option":"Taenia saginata","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"What is the primary reason for the increasing typhoid disease burden in Pakistan?","answers":[{"option":"Drug resistance","bool":true},{"option":"Lack of skilled professionals","bool":false},{"option":"Inaccessibility of healthcare facilities","bool":false},{"option":"Vaccine hesitancy","bool":false},{"option":"Lack of awareness of hygiene practices","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 36-year-old woman, with a known case of HIV infection, has a very low CD4 lymphocyte count and was prescribed treatment. She is non-compliant with her medications and now presents with shortness of breath on exertion and hypoxia. Her chest X-ray reveals fine bilateral infiltrates and the computed tomography (CT) scan reports a bilateral ground-glass appearance. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Pneumococcal pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumocystis pneumonia","bool":true},{"option":"Acute respiratory distress syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Congestive heart failure","bool":false},{"option":"Influenza","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A young patient presents to the clinic with complaints of acute watery diarrhea without abdominal pain, along with vomiting. The stool is rice-watery in nature. What is the most likely cause?","answers":[{"option":"Shigella","bool":false},{"option":"Vibrio cholera","bool":true},{"option":"Amebiasis (E. histolytica)","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella","bool":false},{"option":"Norvovirus","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following is not sexually transmitted?","answers":[{"option":"Molluscum contagiosum","bool":false},{"option":"Trichomoniasis","bool":false},{"option":"Anogenital warts","bool":false},{"option":"Genital candidiasis","bool":true},{"option":"Chlamydia trachomatis","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following is the most common extra-salivary manifestation of mumps after puberty?","answers":[{"option":"Mastitis","bool":false},{"option":"Oophoritis","bool":false},{"option":"Epididymo-orchitis","bool":true},{"option":"Pancreatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Myocarditis","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following antimalarial drugs is effective against the exo-erythrocytic form of malarial parasite?","answers":[{"option":"Pyrimethamine","bool":false},{"option":"Mefloquine","bool":false},{"option":"Chloroquine","bool":false},{"option":"Primaquine","bool":true},{"option":"Quinine","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which history is not significant to ask from a patient who presents with a suspected case of sexually transmitted infection?","answers":[{"option":"Do you have a regular sexual partner at present?","bool":false},{"option":"Do/did you use condom?","bool":false},{"option":"When did you last have sex?","bool":false},{"option":"In your life, have your sexual partners been male, female or both?","bool":false},{"option":"Do you masturbate on regular basis?","bool":true}]},{"id":90,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"SchÃ¼ffnerâs dots are the intracytoplasmic granules found, within infected red cells, due to an infection with which of the following plasmodium species?","answers":[{"option":"Plasmodium knowlesi","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium malariae","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium vivax","bool":true},{"option":"Plasmodium relictum","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium falciparum","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Due to the risk of which of the following is it mandatory for the people traveling to Africa to get vaccinated?","answers":[{"option":"Congo fever","bool":false},{"option":"Malaria","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue","bool":false},{"option":"Lassa fever","bool":false},{"option":"Yellow fever","bool":true}]},{"id":92,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 15-year-old boy comes into the emergency department. He has had a history of fever for the last 2 weeks, initially, low-grade 100 F, followed by high-grade with severe abdominal pain. His blood culture is done as an outpatient is positive for Salmonella typhi with sensitivity to azithromycin and imipenem-cilastatin. An X-ray of the abdomen, erect and supine, shows gas under the right diaphragm. What is the most common site of gut perforation in enteric fever?","answers":[{"option":"Jejunum perforation","bool":false},{"option":"Ascending colon perforation","bool":false},{"option":"Duodenal perforation","bool":false},{"option":"Stomach perforation","bool":false},{"option":"Ileal perforation","bool":true}]},{"id":93,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 20-year-old female presents with a history of fever for five days. She also complains of abdominal pain and constipation. On examination, the temperature is 101 F, the pulse is 68 beats per minute and the rest is unremarkable. The doctor suspects enteric fever. Which of the following is true regarding the investigation?","answers":[{"option":"The sensitivity of typhidot is nearly 100%","bool":false},{"option":"Urine culture is positive in first week","bool":false},{"option":"Stool culture is positive in the first week","bool":false},{"option":"Widal test is the most sensitive","bool":false},{"option":"Blood culture is the most useful diagnostic test at this stage","bool":true}]},{"id":94,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 20-year-old male is given ceftriaxone for the treatment of gonorrhea. Which of the following antibiotic groups does this antibiotic belong to?","answers":[{"option":"Cell membrane inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"DNA synthesis inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"Cell-wall synthesis inhibitor","bool":true},{"option":"Folic acid synthesis inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"Protein synthesis inhibitor","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 25-year-old woman from the Lyari district comes to the emergency department with complaints of severe abdominal pain, nausea, anorexia, flatulence, and abdominal cramps with diarrhea. She tells that she has had the same complaints two weeks before as well. Complete blood count shows marked leukocytosis while the stool examination shows pear-shaped trophozoites. What would the most probable diagnosis be?","answers":[{"option":"Entamoeba histolytica","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial infection","bool":false},{"option":"Cryptosporidium","bool":false},{"option":"Giardia lamblia","bool":true},{"option":"Trichomonas","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 30-year-old male has a road accident, he comes to the emergency department with severe pain and presented with several bruises on different body parts. The physician immediately starts anti-inflammatory agents as a treatment strategy. Which of the following is a hallmark of acute inflammation?","answers":[{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":true},{"option":"Connective tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Granuloma formation","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A child is brought to the clinic for medical consultation with complaints of painful swelling of the parotid gland, fever and difficulty in swallowing. What would be the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Burkitt lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Mumps","bool":true},{"option":"Infectious mononucleosis","bool":false},{"option":"Adenoviral infection","bool":false},{"option":"Influenza","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"The late stage of the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection is acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS). The decline in the number of which of the following cells manifests this stage?","answers":[{"option":"CD8+ T cells","bool":false},{"option":"CD4+ T cells","bool":true},{"option":"CD40 cells","bool":false},{"option":"CD28 cells","bool":false},{"option":"MHC class I cells","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following antimalarial drugs is used for the treatment of chloroquine-resistant falciparum malaria?","answers":[{"option":"Proguanil","bool":false},{"option":"Mefloquine","bool":false},{"option":"Artemisinin","bool":true},{"option":"Sulfadoxine","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrimethamine","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 35-year-old male consults to physician after being bitten by a stranded dog within 24 hours. What post-exposure prophylaxis regime will the doctor offer him after local wound care or cleaning?","answers":[{"option":"10 IU/kg human rabies immunoglobulin (HRIG) plus 5 doses of 1 ml human diploid cell vaccine (HDCV)","bool":false},{"option":"20 IU/kg human rabies immunoglobulin (HRIG) alone","bool":false},{"option":"5 doses of 1 ml human diploid cell vaccine (HDCV); intramuscular (I/M)","bool":false},{"option":"20 IU/kg human rabies immunoglobulin (HRIG) plus 3 doses of 1 ml human diploid cell vaccine (HDCV)","bool":false},{"option":"20 IU/kg human rabies immunoglobulin (HRIG) plus 5 doses of 1 ml human diploid cell vaccine (HDCV)","bool":true}]},{"id":101,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A doctor is called in sessions court as a witness. During cross-examination, he utters an indecent remark on the defense counsel, which is brought to the knowledge of the judge who gives minimum punishment to the doctor. Which of the following would it be?","answers":[{"option":"Warning in writing with copy to the employer","bool":false},{"option":"Fee of Rs. 50 only","bool":false},{"option":"Detaining him in the court till rising of the court for the day","bool":true},{"option":"Fee of Rs. 100 only","bool":false},{"option":"Fee of Rs. 10 only","bool":false}]},{"id":102,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A patient comes to the emergency department with a history of prolonged cough, fever and chest infection. He is diagnosed with a case of tuberculosis after getting confirmation from the report of biopsy. Which one of the following would have been the identifying feature of tuberculosis?","answers":[{"option":"Infiltration of eosinophils","bool":false},{"option":"Congested blood vessels","bool":false},{"option":"Accumulation of neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Granuloma formation","bool":true},{"option":"Collection of serous fluid","bool":false}]},{"id":103,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A patient comes to the emergency department with fever, abdominal cramps, and a history of passing only a small amount of loose stools. Lab findings show mucous, red blood cells, and white blood cells in the stool sample. Which of the following best describes this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Food poisoning","bool":false},{"option":"Dysentery","bool":true},{"option":"Indigestion","bool":false},{"option":"Watery diarrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Bloody diarrhea","bool":false}]},{"id":104,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A very effective vaccine for which of the following is available to prevent diarrhea in children?","answers":[{"option":"Shigella","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella","bool":false},{"option":"Vibrio cholerae","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Rota virus","bool":true}]},{"id":105,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A young male develops a high-grade fever intermittent in nature and occurring every 48 hours. Later on, his laboratory report reveals that he has vivax malaria. Which subtype fever does he have?","answers":[{"option":"Tertian fever","bool":true},{"option":"Relapsing fever","bool":false},{"option":"Quotidian fever","bool":false},{"option":"Quartan fever","bool":false},{"option":"Malignant tertian fever","bool":false}]},{"id":106,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A young male presents with painless profuse diarrhea. He is passing a large volume of stool flecked with mucus. He presents to the emergency response department dehydrated and in a state of shock. Which of the following is an appropriate statement if cholera is suspected?","answers":[{"option":"Hyperchlorhydria facilitates the passage of cholera bacilli into the small intestine","bool":false},{"option":"It releases GABA which is responsible for its secretory effect","bool":false},{"option":"Cholera toxin is an enterotoxin","bool":true},{"option":"Cholera toxin releases 5-hydroxytryptamine from enterochromaffin cells in the gut","bool":false},{"option":"Diarrhea occurs because of vibrio cholera invasive action","bool":false}]},{"id":107,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 34-year-old intravenous drug abuser comes with bloody diarrhea for 3 months. Which of the following is the most common protozoan causing bloody diarrhea?","answers":[{"option":"Microsporidium","bool":false},{"option":"Cryptosporidium","bool":false},{"option":"Entamoeba histolytica","bool":true},{"option":"Isospora belli","bool":false},{"option":"Giardia lamblia","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Among all the types of leprosy, which of the following has a good prognosis and may even heal itself?","answers":[{"option":"Borderline tuberculoid","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculoid leprosy","bool":true},{"option":"Borderline leprosy","bool":false},{"option":"Borderline lepromatous leprosy","bool":false},{"option":"Lepromatous leprosy","bool":false}]},{"id":109,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"An antiviral drug ritonavir acts by inhibiting which of the following enzymes?","answers":[{"option":"Peptidyl transferase","bool":false},{"option":"Beta-lactamase","bool":false},{"option":"Reverse transcriptase","bool":false},{"option":"Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) protease","bool":true},{"option":"Hydrolase","bool":false}]},{"id":110,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"In which of the following conditions can the anti-inflammatory effect of chloroquine be used?","answers":[{"option":"Cellulitis","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatic fever","bool":false},{"option":"Myocarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatoid arthritis","bool":true}]},{"id":111,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Chronic granulomatous inflammation is microscopically characterized by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Fibrous tissue formation","bool":false},{"option":"New blood vessels formation (angiogenesis)","bool":false},{"option":"Circumscribed collection of epithelioid and multinucleated giant cells","bool":true},{"option":"Sheets of epithelioid cells","bool":false},{"option":"Diffuse infiltration by lymphocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":112,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Complications of measles can be very severe in certain cases. Which of the following is not considered a complication occurring several years after the episode of measles?","answers":[{"option":"Panencephalitis","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Orchitis","bool":true},{"option":"Meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Otitis media","bool":false}]},{"id":113,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 16-year-old male presents with a complaint of high-grade fever with chills and rigors for five days along with severe body aches and pains. On peripheral examination, the patient is febrile. On systemic examination, no significant finding was found except his petechial rashes all over the extremities. What would the most likely diagnosis be?","answers":[{"option":"Dengue fever","bool":true},{"option":"Mumps","bool":false},{"option":"Measles","bool":false},{"option":"Malaria","bool":false},{"option":"Typhoid","bool":false}]},{"id":114,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following is the more frequent cause of bloody diarrhea in children?","answers":[{"option":"Vibrio cholera","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella","bool":false},{"option":"Shigella","bool":true},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Rota virus","bool":false}]},{"id":115,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following is the characteristic of dengue?","answers":[{"option":"Fever without rash","bool":false},{"option":"Transient rash","bool":false},{"option":"Rash without fever","bool":false},{"option":"Neither rash nor fever","bool":false},{"option":"Fever with rash","bool":true}]},{"id":116,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Elephantiasis is caused by blockage of the lymphatic system. Which of the following is the most common cause of elephantiasis?","answers":[{"option":"Ancylostoma duodenale","bool":false},{"option":"Wuchereria bancrofti","bool":true},{"option":"Trichinella spiralis","bool":false},{"option":"Enterobius vermicularis","bool":false},{"option":"Trichuris trichiura","bool":false}]},{"id":117,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following is endotoxin, an integral part of?","answers":[{"option":"Fungal cell wall","bool":false},{"option":"Gram negative rods and cocci","bool":true},{"option":"Gram positive rods","bool":false},{"option":"Gram positive cocci","bool":false},{"option":"Normal cells of body","bool":false}]},{"id":118,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Fever, a biological effect of endotoxin, occurs due to the release of which of the following endogenous pyrogens?","answers":[{"option":"Interleukin-4","bool":false},{"option":"Interleukin-5","bool":false},{"option":"Interleukin-2","bool":false},{"option":"Interleukin-12","bool":false},{"option":"Interleukin-1","bool":true}]},{"id":119,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A patient presents with complaints of fever and body ache for the past two days. What is the best initial test for the diagnosis of dengue fever?","answers":[{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false},{"option":"Erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR) and c-reactive protein (CRP) tests","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue serology","bool":false},{"option":"Liver function tests","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue nonstructural protein 1 (NS1) test","bool":true}]},{"id":120,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"In a male diagnosed with a sexually transmitted infection, microscopic examination of fluid from the lesions reveals spiral microorganisms that can not be stained by Gram's staining procedure. What would the microorganism most likely be?","answers":[{"option":"Chlamydia species","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Borrelia species","bool":false},{"option":"Treponema pallidum","bool":true},{"option":"Neisseria gonorrhoeae","bool":false}]},{"id":121,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"In a stool sample of a 10-year-old Muslim child admitted for abdominal pain, flat ribbon-like segments with scolices are seen. What would the most probable diagnosis be?","answers":[{"option":"Ancylostoma duodenale","bool":false},{"option":"Enterobius vermicularis","bool":false},{"option":"Taenia saginata","bool":true},{"option":"Trichuris trichiura","bool":false},{"option":"Taenia solium","bool":false}]},{"id":122,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Leprosy is a chronic granulomatous disease causing multiple deformities of extremities. Which of the following statements is correct regarding its incubation period?","answers":[{"option":"The incubation period averages several hours","bool":false},{"option":"The incubation period averages few months","bool":false},{"option":"The incubation period averages few weeks","bool":false},{"option":"The incubation period averages few days","bool":false},{"option":"The incubation period averages several years","bool":true}]},{"id":123,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Leprosy is caused by Mycobacterium leprae, characterized by loss of sensation in the periphery. Which of the following is true regarding the duration of treatment of tuberculoid leprosy?","answers":[{"option":"Treatment is given for one year","bool":false},{"option":"Treatment is given for six months","bool":true},{"option":"Treatment is given for two years","bool":false},{"option":"Treatment is given for one month","bool":false},{"option":"Treatment is given for three months","bool":false}]},{"id":124,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Measles is primarily a childhood disease characterized by fever, runny nose, cough, and maculopapular rash. What is its diagnosis usually done by?","answers":[{"option":"Rise in antibody titer","bool":false},{"option":"History and physical examination","bool":true},{"option":"Virus cell culture","bool":false},{"option":"RNA hybridization test","bool":false},{"option":"Polymerase chain reaction","bool":false}]},{"id":125,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following is the most sensitive test for diagnosis of liver hydatid cyst?","answers":[{"option":"Ultrasound of the abdomen","bool":false},{"option":"Fine needle aspiration (FNA)","bool":false},{"option":"Serology","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray of the abdomen","bool":false},{"option":"Computed tomography (CT) of the abdomen","bool":true}]},{"id":126,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following organisms causes diarrheal disease in almost 100% of the children by the age of five years?","answers":[{"option":"Entamoeba histolytica","bool":false},{"option":"Shigella","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella","bool":false},{"option":"Candida","bool":false},{"option":"Rota virus","bool":true}]},{"id":127,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following results in the primary immune defect of acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS)?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased cellular immunity","bool":false},{"option":"Low synthesis of immunoglobulin","bool":false},{"option":"Reduction of number and effectiveness of CD4+ T cells due to killing induced by human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)","bool":true},{"option":"Killing of CD4+ T cells due to antibody-dependent cytotoxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Inactivation of phagocytic cells","bool":false}]},{"id":128,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following is most accurate regarding human papillomavirus (HPV)?","answers":[{"option":"Human papillomavirus causes genital warts and cervical cancer","bool":true},{"option":"The capsid protein P2 of human papillomavirus activates the C-scars oncogene in human cells","bool":false},{"option":"Blood and blood products are important modes of transmission","bool":false},{"option":"Human papillomavirus causes the infection of upper respiratory tract and lower respiratory tract mainly","bool":false},{"option":"Human papillomavirus is an enveloped virus with RNA genome","bool":false}]},{"id":129,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"On the basis of which of the following can Shigella be differentiated from Salmonella?","answers":[{"option":"Having very low infectious dose (ID50)","bool":true},{"option":"Being gram negative","bool":false},{"option":"Growth on MacConkey's medium","bool":false},{"option":"Being non-lactose fermenters","bool":false},{"option":"Being able to produce hydrogen sulphide (H2S)","bool":false}]},{"id":130,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"In which of the following does the sporogony take place?","answers":[{"option":"Environment","bool":false},{"option":"Mosquito gut","bool":true},{"option":"Salivary glands of mosquito","bool":false},{"option":"Liver cells","bool":false},{"option":"Human blood","bool":false}]},{"id":131,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"In the pathogenesis of which of the following diseases is the superantigen production by Staphylococcus aureus involved?","answers":[{"option":"Impetigo","bool":false},{"option":"Scalded skin syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Septicemia","bool":false},{"option":"Food poisoning","bool":true},{"option":"Osteomyelitis","bool":false}]},{"id":132,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"If a multi-bacillary leprosy patient, treated with standard fixed-duration multi-drug therapy, starts having relapses, what among the following regimen should be started?","answers":[{"option":"Rifampin + dapsone + clofazimine","bool":true},{"option":"Ofloxacin  + minocycline + clarithromycin","bool":false},{"option":"Clofazimine + ofloxacin + minocycline","bool":false},{"option":"Rifampin + dapsone + ofloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Clofazimine + ofloxacin + clarithromycin","bool":false}]},{"id":133,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"What will be the best specimen to find Entamoeba histolytica cysts?","answers":[{"option":"Urine of the diarrheal patient","bool":false},{"option":"Blood of asymptomatic carrier","bool":false},{"option":"Blood of the diarrheal patient","bool":false},{"option":"Stool of the diarrheal patient","bool":false},{"option":"Stool of asymptomatic carrier","bool":true}]},{"id":134,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"In which stage or phase of human acquired immunodeficiency (HIV) virus infection is the term 'acquired immunodeficiency syndrome' (AIDS) used to denote the disease?","answers":[{"option":"Infective period of human acquired immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection","bool":false},{"option":"Initial phase of human acquired immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection","bool":false},{"option":"Incubation period of human acquired immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection","bool":false},{"option":"Last stage of human acquired immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection","bool":true},{"option":"Convalescent phase of human acquired immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection","bool":false}]},{"id":135,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A certain tapeworm uses two elongated sucking grooves to attach to the intestinal wall. It may lead to vitamin B-12 deficiency, resulting in megaloblastic anemia. Which of the following worms is this?","answers":[{"option":"Ascaris lumbricoides","bool":false},{"option":"Taenia solium","bool":false},{"option":"Echinococcus granulosus","bool":false},{"option":"Diphyllobothrium latum","bool":true},{"option":"Taenia saginata","bool":false}]},{"id":136,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following statements is true regarding Plasmodium falciparum?","answers":[{"option":"Anemia is not significant","bool":false},{"option":"Splenomegaly is not a feature","bool":false},{"option":"Relapses occur every 3 months","bool":false},{"option":"It causes malignant tertian infection","bool":true},{"option":"Characteristically, paroxysm occurs every 72 hours","bool":false}]},{"id":137,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Viral hemorrhagic fever is caused by a group of viruses that mostly attack the vascular system. Which of the following virus families does the dengue virus belong to?","answers":[{"option":"Bunyaviridae","bool":false},{"option":"Arenaviridae","bool":false},{"option":"Ebola","bool":false},{"option":"Flaviviridae","bool":true},{"option":"Floviviridae","bool":false}]},{"id":138,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Complete blood count (CBC) examination of the blood taken from a patient with a history of fever reveals distorted red blood cells (RBCs) double of its size with SchÃ¼ffner's dots. Which of the following protozoa is responsible for that picture?","answers":[{"option":"Plasmodium ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium vivax","bool":true},{"option":"Plasmodium malariae","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium falciparum","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium knowlesi","bool":false}]},{"id":139,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Dengue is also known as breakbone fever. Which of the following statements is true regarding the causative organism of this disease?","answers":[{"option":"It is a protozoan parasite","bool":false},{"option":"It is a DNA enveloped virus","bool":false},{"option":"It is a RNA non-enveloped virus","bool":false},{"option":"It is a RNA enveloped virus","bool":true},{"option":"It is a DNA non-enveloped virus","bool":false}]},{"id":140,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"In the life cycle of parasites, what is the 'definitive host' defined as?","answers":[{"option":"A host who is an obligatory part of life cycle","bool":false},{"option":"A host in which asexual reproduction occurs","bool":false},{"option":"A host in which life cycle can end","bool":false},{"option":"A host in which sexual reproduction occurs","bool":true},{"option":"A host that acts as a vector in transporting the parasite from infected host","bool":false}]},{"id":141,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Why is the infection with Plasmodium falciparum called 'malignant malaria'?","answers":[{"option":"Causes malignancies","bool":false},{"option":"Irregular paroxysms","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple infection in red blood cells","bool":false},{"option":"Adherence and blockage of capillaries of internal organs","bool":true},{"option":"Absence of relapses","bool":false}]},{"id":142,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following is an appropriate drug in the treatment of acute enteric fever?","answers":[{"option":"Ceftriaxone","bool":true},{"option":"Chloramphenicol","bool":false},{"option":"Ampicillin","bool":false},{"option":"Sulphonamide","bool":false},{"option":"Amoxicillin","bool":false}]},{"id":143,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"The present-day societies have high expectations from medical professionals regarding their ideal ethical practice. The broader guidelines can be learned from the subject of medical ethics. What does this subject deal with?","answers":[{"option":"Moral values to be observed by medical professional in their practice","bool":true},{"option":"Interpersonal relationships are the basic requirement","bool":false},{"option":"Confidentiality of patient record as an ideal ethical practice","bool":false},{"option":"Research ethics should be made mandatory","bool":false},{"option":"Implied contract and its details","bool":false}]},{"id":144,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of perianal pruritus?","answers":[{"option":"Pinworm infection","bool":true},{"option":"Loiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Whipworm infection","bool":false},{"option":"Filariasis","bool":false},{"option":"Trichinosis","bool":false}]},{"id":145,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2020","question":"A 22-year-old student comes with a positive test for the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV). He is taking intravenous drugs for the past year. His physical examination is unremarkable. His laboratory tests and investigations are all fine, and the CD4+ lymphocyte count is within the normal range at 750. What would the best course of action be to start antiretroviral therapy?","answers":[{"option":"Once he has stopped using drugs","bool":false},{"option":"When his CD4+ cell count is below 300","bool":false},{"option":"When he starts to show initial signs of infection","bool":false},{"option":"When his human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) viral load is approaching 1 million","bool":false},{"option":"Immediately","bool":true}]}]
export default arr